A Finding Aid to the Adolf Dehn Papers, 1912-1987, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Scrapbooks, 1912-1968; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 6-7: 0.5 linear feet)
  The other scrapbook (Scrapbook II) contains similar items, the bulk of which have remained affixed to the pages. Although unbound, the pages are stored within the front and back covers. Dehn's faded monogram is visible on the front cover. This scrapbook begins with a high school graduation announcement from 1914 and contains clippings and exhibition announcements that span from that early date to 1942. It also includes a loose 1929 announcement from the Weyhe Gallery, which contains a brief note to his mother and sister reporting early sales of his work form the exhibition.
  Additional clippings, exhibition announcements, as well as examples of Dehn's editorial cartoons, magazine covers, and Christmas card designs can be found in the Printed Materials series.
  The large sheets of Scrapbook I, as well as oversize loose items, have been arranged in rough chronological order. The clippings and other detached items from Scrapbook I have been arranged by format and date into several standard sized files. Due to the presence of adhesive residue, these files are heavily interleaved.
  - Scrapbook - Boardman Robinson Editorial Cartoons, 1912-1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook I, circa 1912-1945; Archival Resource Key; (Comprised of loose oversize sheets, distributed amongst 6 folders, located in Box 7) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook I - Loose Items, circa 1912-1945; Archival Resource Key; (6 folders; oversize loose items are located in Box 7) (Box 6, Folder 8-13)
  - Scrapbook II, circa 1914-1942; Archival Resource Key; (Oversize scrapbook is located in Box 7) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Extra Items from Scrapbook, circa 1917-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Oversize Scrapbook I Sheets and Loose Items, circa 1912-1945; Archival Resource Key; (related items located in Box 6, Folders 8-13) (Box 7)
  - Oversize Scrapbook II, circa 1914-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
- Artwork, circa 1920-1945; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; (Box 6; 3 folders)
  This series contains sketches and artwork by Dehn and others. Items include 4 sketches attributed to Adolf Dehn; graphite and ink sketches attributed to Eileen Hall Lake, which were originally stored with her poetry journal that can be found in the subseries Writings by Others; and an etching by S.W. Hayter.
  Artwork files are arranged in alphabetical order by the artist's last name.
  - Sketches attributed to Adolf Dehn, 1929-1935 and undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Etching by S.W. Hayter, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Sketches attributed to Eileen Hall Lake, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Photographs, circa 1912-1961; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 6 and 8; 8 folders)
  Photographs in this series include a vintage gelatin silver print portrait of Adolf Dehn by André Kertész;, vintage photographs of Dehn with family members; Dehn with friends, including Lawrence Barnett, Federico Castellon, Albert Christ-Janer; with his former wife Mura; two sets of photobooth photographs taken on separate occasions with Eileen Hall Lake and Willis Bock; and a series of photographs of Adolf and Virginia taken at Atelier Desjobert. Many of these vintage photographs are annotated on the verso. There is also a panoramic view of Camp Wadsworth, Spartenburg, South Carolina, where Dehn was detained as a conscientious objector of World War I. Also found are several photographic reproductions of Dehn's drawings, lithographs, and watercolors.
  - Adolf Dehn Portrait by André Kertész, circa 1928; Archival Resource Key; (copy print and negative in folder; matted vintage print is located in Box 8) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Adolf Dehn Portraits, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key; (2 vintage portraits) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Adolf Dehn Alone and With Others, circa 1912-1961; Archival Resource Key; (97 vintage photographs) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Willis Bock Portraits, circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key; (4 studio portraits of Willis Bock) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Eileen Hall Lake and others, circa 1934-1943; Archival Resource Key; (27 photographs) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Etta Lee, Yo-Hay-Tong, and Unidentified People, circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key; (6 photographs) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Panoramic View of Camp Wadsworth, Spartanburg, South Carolina, 1918; Archival Resource Key; (Oversize photograph torn in 4 pieces; located in Box 7) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1929-1958; Archival Resource Key; (16 photographs) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Oversize Adolf Dehn Portrait by André Kertész, circa 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
  - Oversize Panoramic View of Camp Wadsworth, Spartanburg, South Carolina, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 8)